=A Puppetry=
= دمية =
=Episode 6=
= الحلقة 6 =
Mind what you said.
مانع ما قلته.
Instead of
بدلاً من
honing on your own techniques,
شحذ التقنيات الخاصة بك ،
you talk behind others' backs.
تتحدث خلف ظهور الآخرين.
What a bunch of naysayers.
يا لها من حفنة من الرافضين.
Who are you?
من أنت؟
I'm here to teach you a lesson.
أنا هنا لأعلمك درسًا.
Eldest Martial Brother.
الأخ الأكبر.
What's the matter?
ما الأمر؟
Run.
يجري.
Chase after them.
مطاردة وراءهم.
Don't you run.
لا تركض.
(Rescued from drowning.)
(أنقذ من الغرق).
(Encounter, Rescued)
(لقاء ، منقذ)
(How is she supposed to fall into the river?
(كيف يفترض أن تسقط في النهر؟
(Didn't he say we should look for a stage?)
(ألم يقل أننا يجب أن نبحث عن مرحلة؟)
(Why did he bring me here?)
(لماذا أحضرني إلى هنا؟)
(Is he...)
(هل هو...)
Look.
نظرة.
Wait for me.
الانتظار لي.
(So that's what should happen.)
(هذا ما يجب أن يحدث.)
I like this one.
أحببت هذه.
(Is he buying me new clothes?)
(هل يشتري لي ملابس جديدة؟)
Try them on.
جربهم.
- Go. - Come.
- يذهب.  - يأتي.
Careful.
حذر.
Do you have money?
هل لديك المال؟
If it fits you,
إذا كان يناسبك ،
money is not an issue.
المال ليس هو القضية.
Mister, you pamper your wife.
سيد ، أنت تدلل زوجتك.
She's not my wife.
إنها ليست زوجتي.
She's my friend.
هي صديقي.
(I don't need)
(لست بحاجة)
(a girlfriend who eats as much as she does.)
(صديقة تأكل بقدر ما تأكل.)
Liu Xiaoxiao.
ليو شياوكسياو.
Xiaoxiao!
شياوكسياو!
Go.
يذهب.
Inform Madam Hua.
أبلغ سيدتي هوا.
It's time for business.
حان وقت العمل.
(Chunman Brothel) Mister!
(تشونمان بيت دعارة) مستر!
Come play with us.
تعال والعب معنا.
Let go of me.
ترك لي.
Sit down.
اجلس.
Hold her in place.
ثبتها في مكانها.
Let go of me.
ترك لي.
You won't be able to escape even if we release you now.
لن تتمكن من الهروب حتى لو أطلقنا سراحك الآن.
In my Chunman Brothel,
في بيت الدعارة الخاص بي في Chunman ،
even a fairy
حتى الجنية
cannot fly away.
لا يمكن أن تطير بعيدا.
Cai Die already scouted you out
كاي داي اكتشفك بالفعل
for me.
لي.
We wanted
أردنا
to lure your husband out
لإغراء زوجك بالخروج
before asking you to go to another shop
قبل أن يطلب منك الذهاب إلى متجر آخر
but somehow,
لكن بطريقة ما ،
you walked into our place.
دخلت مكاننا.
- I'm telling you. - Bring her back here.
- أنا أخبرك.  - اعدها الى هنا.
This is against the law.
هذا هو ضد القانون.
I will report you.
سأبلغ عنك.
How unfortunate.
يالسوء الحظ.
When you were sound asleep,
عندما كنت نائمًا ،
you signed here.
قمت بالتوقيع هنا.
Song Keyang will be here
سيكون Song Keyang هنا
to punish all of you.
لمعاقبتكم جميعًا.
I'm afraid
أنا خائف
your husband cannot look after you.
زوجك لا يستطيع أن يعتني بك.
I had someone take him away
كان لدي شخص ما أخذه بعيدا
and throw him out of the Mai Prefecture.
وإلقائه خارج محافظة ماي.
(Liu Residence, Linglong Town)
(سكن ليو ، مدينة لينجلونج)
(Buying freedom, Chunman Brothel, Liu Residence)
(شراء الحرية ، بيت دعارة تشونمان ، سكن ليو)
(This is the place.)
(هذا هو المكان.)
(Liu Residence)
(سكن ليو)
(It's my time)
(حان وقتي)
(to shine now.)
(للتألق الآن.)
Just accept your fate.
فقط اقبل مصيرك.
Read
اقرأ
all these books now.
كل هذه الكتب الآن.
If you make a lots of money,
إذا جنيت الكثير من المال ،
you'll live comfortably too.
ستعيش بشكل مريح أيضًا.
Let me out of here.
اسمحوا لي أن أخرج من هنا.
It's all my fault.
هذا كله خطأي.
I dragged him into this.
لقد جرته إلى هذا.
I wonder
انا اتعجب
what he is doing now.
ماذا يفعل الان.
So handsome!
وسيم جدا!
Where does this musician come from?
من أين أتى هذا الموسيقي؟
He's dashing
إنه محطم
and gentlemanly.
ورجل نبيل.
(General Liu, a retired general)
(الجنرال ليو ، جنرال متقاعد)
(Just like)
(تماما مثل)
(doing a task,)
(القيام بمهمة ،)
you need to use your brain.
تحتاج إلى استخدام عقلك.
Don't just brute force everything.
لا تكتفي بالقوة الغاشمة على كل شيء.
That's how you find an efficient solution.
هكذا تجد حلاً فعالاً.
Efficient solution...
حل فعال ...
So you had an epiphany?
إذن كان لديك عيد الغطاس؟
Indeed.
في الواقع.
Madam Hua.
سيدتي هوا.
I
أنا
grow up to be a performer.
يكبر ليكون مؤدًا.
I can perform a puppet show.
يمكنني أداء عرض للدمى المتحركة.
Now that fate has willed me
الآن شاء هذا القدر
to come to Chunman Brothel,
للمجيء إلى بيت دعارة تشونمان ،
I figure
أنا أظن
that for the upcoming puppetry festival,
لمهرجان الدمى القادم ،
I
أنا
can participate in it
يمكن أن تشارك فيه
on behalf of Chunman Brothel.
نيابة عن بيت دعارة تشونمان.
With this promotional event,
مع هذا الحدث الترويجي ،
if the performance is a resounding success,
إذا كان الأداء ناجحًا باهرًا ،
Chunman Brothel
بيت دعارة تشونمان
will become famous
سوف تصبح مشهورة
and it will attract more clients
وسيجذب المزيد من العملاء
to come here.
لتأتي إلى هنا.
And the price for my service
وسعر خدمتي
will increase too.
سيزيد أيضا.
Isn't this
أليس هذا
killing two birds
قتل عصفورين
with one stone?
بحجر واحد؟
Right.
الصحيح.
Madam Hua.
سيدتي هوا.
Look.
نظرة.
This
هذه
is the story between the Celestial Emperor and Yuji.
هي القصة بين الإمبراطور السماوي ويوجي.
You might not know
قد لا تعرف
but it's very famous
لكنها مشهورة جدا
in Chenmen Town.
في Chenmen Town.
A rod puppet show
عرض عرائس قضيب
with an elegant dance.
برقصة أنيقة.
Together,
معاً،
they are mesmerizing.
إنهم يفتنون.
And then, Chunman Brothel
وبعد ذلك ، بيت دعارة تشونمان
will be crowded,
ستكون مزدحمة ،
and packed.
ومعبأة.
You have no idea.
ليس لديك فكرة.
Right.
الصحيح.
Oh, Madam Hua.
أوه ، سيدتي هوا.
I need a favor from you.
انا بحاجة الى صالح منك.
Yes?
نعم؟
Find me Song Keyang.
تجد لي Song Keyang.
Song Keyang?
سونغ كيانج؟
I'm Song Keyang.
أنا سونغ كيانغ.
Insolence.
الوقاحة.
There's an undercurrent
هناك تيار خفي
to your music just now.
لموسيقاك الآن.
You hardly hear this kind
بالكاد تسمع هذا النوع
of song in the Central Plains.
الأغنية في السهول الوسطى.
I
أنا
have only heard it once in the desert.
سمعته مرة واحدة فقط في الصحراء.
Speak now.
تكلم الآن.
Who exactly are you?
من انت بالضبط
Is there a need
هل هناك حاجة
to put music in all sorts of categories?
لوضع الموسيقى في جميع أنواع الفئات؟
Forget that I'm a wandering musician.
نسيت أنني موسيقي متجول.
A song
أغنية
should transcend geography.
يجب أن يتجاوز الجغرافيا.
Spreading
ينتشر
good music to other places,
موسيقى جيدة في أماكن أخرى ،
to a wider audience.
لجمهور أوسع.
That's the true calling of a musician.
هذه هي الدعوة الحقيقية للموسيقي.
The rest
البقية
is none of my business.
ليس من أعمالي.
You might not know
قد لا تعرف
but he is a famous musician
لكنه موسيقي مشهور
in Chenmen Town.
في Chenmen Town.
Without him, my play...
بدونه ، مسرحيتي ...
If there is a small misplay,
إذا كان هناك خطأ بسيط ،
my value will...
قيمتي سوف ...
Fine.
بخير.
I'll trust you just this once.
سأثق بك هذه المرة فقط.
Don't pull any dirty tricks on me.
لا تسحب أي حيل قذرة علي.
If you're sabotaging my business...
إذا كنت تخرب عملي ...
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I will do my best
سأبذل قصارى جهدي
for you.
لك.
The Chen Theater Troupe
فرقة مسرح تشن
all died in a fire?
ماتوا جميعا في حريق؟
I suppose
أفترض
I'll never get the chance
لن تسنح لي الفرصة ابدا
to watch a good puppet show again.
لمشاهدة عرض جيد للدمى مرة أخرى.
But I heard successor
لكنني سمعت خليفة
of the Chen Theater Troupe,
من فرقة مسرح تشين ،
Liu Xiaoxiao,
ليو شياوكسياو ،
survived.
نجا.
She was tricked into prostitution.
تم خداعها في الدعارة.
Successor of the Chen Theater Troupe?
خليفة فرقة مسرح تشين؟
Prostitution?
بغاء؟
♪The dusk outside the window is spreading♪
♪ الغسق خارج النافذة ينتشر
♪The lanterns light up with anticipation♪
الفوانيس تضيء بترقب
♪The sea of lights illuminates the entire theater♪
♪ بحر الأضواء ينير المسرح بأكمله
♪The galaxy sprawls across the sky♪
المجرة تمتد عبر السماء ♪
♪The moon shows itself♪
القمر يظهر نفسه ♪
♪Gazing at the myriad lives♪
التحديق في حياة لا تعد ولا تحصى ♪
♪The bell chimes and the lady dances♪
يدق الجرس والسيدة ترقص
♪Her movements are mysterious and graceful♪
حركاتها غامضة ورشيقة ♪
♪A woman can solicit cheers and applause too♪
♪ يمكن للمرأة أن تلتمس الهتافات والتصفيق أيضًا ♪
♪Chatters fill the well-lit hall♪
♪ الدردشة تملأ القاعة المضاءة جيدًا
♪Holding a red candle by the stage♪
♪ عقد شمعة حمراء على خشبة المسرح ♪
♪Witnessing the blooming and wilting, oh, the freedom♪
مشاهدة التفتح والذبول يا الحرية
♪The theater welcomes you♪
المسرح يرحب بك ♪